The next action we will take on
data is to update existing data.
I have typed and run a SELECT statement to
select everything from the BikeRepairs table.
We see that the start date is incorrect on one of
the bike orders, and we want to change that start
date. I will comment out the select statement,
and let's focus on this UPDATE statement.
Notice that when we start an update, we always
update a table, not a column within a table.
The SET statement actually sets the column and
value to be updated. This next part is critical.
We always want a WHERE clause within an UPDATE
statement. Why? Think about this for a minute.
If we ran this without a WHERE clause, what do
you think would happen? Every record in this
table would get a new start date. We do not
want that, so we always want to use the WHERE
clause to specify what is being updated, in this
case, this BikeRepairID. I will execute this,
and the update has been made. I will
then run this SELECT statement again,
and we see the updated record here. One
other reason to be so careful with this
is that changes to data are not undoable like
they are in a program such as Excel, which is why
it is so important to have a WHERE clause in an
UPDATE statement to define what is being updated.